Lisa Over

1651 Hillsdale Ave. Pittsburgh, PA 15216 412-654-8247 • lisa@lisaover.com • www.lisaover.com

Career Summary

Professional in statistics and computer science with a diverse background in education and communication.

- Tenacious and resourceful programmer with experience developing data management and modeling programs, user interfaces, and usable and accessible websites.
- Knowledgeable statistician trained in data visualization, linear and logistic regression modeling, statistical inference, experimental design, statistical computing, and applied probability.
- Detail-oriented writer and editor with experience developing statistical reports, user manuals, online help systems, and promotional documentation.

Skills

| Data Science | Computer Programming | Communication & Design |
|------------------|----------------------|------------------------|
| SAS, R | Java | Photoshop |
| VBA | PHP, JSP | Illustrator |
| SQL | JavaScript | Teaching |
| SSIS, SSAS, DQS | XML, XSLT | Writing |
| MS Access, Excel | HTML, CSS | Editing |

Professional Organizations and Conferences

American Statistical Association • USCOTS 2015 • Association for Computing Machinery

Related Experience

Business Analyst Intern

Management Science Associates, Pittsburgh, PA

July 2015 to Oct 2015

- Assisted higher-level analysts on a variety of market research projects, which involved creating
 graphs, data summaries, and regression model reports for a new brand volume forecast and an
 analysis of out of stock SKUs.
- Wrote SAS procedures and macros to organize and summarize data and run models; data organization tasks involved extensive use of SQL.
- Wrote visual basic scripts to perform calculations and to create report summaries and charts automatically, which made data preparation more efficient and less prone to error.

Adjunct Professor, Business Statistics

Duquesne University, Pittsburgh, PA

Aug 2016 to Present

- Design and deliver lessons to engage students with real-world and hands-on activities.
- Modify instruction based on student questions and performance.
- Incorporate projects that model the data analysis process and develop statistical thinking and technical writing skills.
- Monitor student progress through formative assessments and assignments and provide feedback to students through re-teaching and comments.
- Work closely with students individually and in small groups to identify weaknesses and areas for improvement.

Lisa Over Page 2

Work Experience

Technical Writer Contractor

Bombardier via Oxford Solutions, Pittsburgh, PA

Feb 2016 to June 2016

- Planned and organized text for the user interface, data management, and security components of the Positive Train Control System.
- Wrote quality, usable, and technically accurate documentation using communication and organizational skills, attention to detail, and fact-checking.
- Collaborated with development team to understand and communicate technical concepts to the system maintainer, system administrator, and database administrator.

Web Designer and Administrator

Trailmarker (self-employed), Pittsburgh, PA

Aug 2006 to Present

- Design and maintain websites for visual appeal, accessibility, usability, and maintainability using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and PHP.
- Work closely with clients to edit, organize, and present their information effectively.

Computer Support Coordinator

Allegheny Center Alliance Church, Pittsburgh, PA

Feb 1999 to Feb 2001

- Managed 35 workstations and several printers connected to a Novell server.
- Interacted with 28 users with varying levels of computer skills. Analyzed users' needs and designed templates and processes that helped them accomplish daily tasks and reach long-term goals.
- Surveyed, prioritized, and solved hardware and software problems by training users, troubleshooting the system, or contacting a technical volunteer.

Technical Writer

PHW INC., Pittsburgh, PA

Nov 1996 to Aug 1998

• Improved user manuals for the electronic train control systems designed and manufactured by PHW, INC by editing for grammar, consistent language and style, and technical clarity.

Technical Communicator

Transarc Corporation (IBM Pittsburgh Lab), Pittsburgh, PA

July 1994 to Nov 1996

- Planned, organized, and designed text and graphics of software user manuals, online help systems, and release notes for several releases of Transarc's Distributed File System software.
- Wrote quality, usable, and technically accurate documentation using communication and organizational skills, attention to detail, and fact-checking.
- Collaborated with development team to understand and communicate technical concepts, benefits, and procedures to the target audience.

Education

Master of Science in Computational Mathematics, 2015 Duquesne University, Pittsburgh, PA

Teacher Certification in Mathematics 7-12, 2012

Robert Morris University, Pittsburgh, PA

Bachelor of Science in Scientific and Technical Communication, 1994

Specialization: Mathematics and Computer Science Bowling Green State University, Bowling Green, OH